Register of the Joseph Warren Stilwell papers 51001
Hoover Institution Archives
- American Expeditionary Forces, IV Army Corps File, 1912-1939
  - Intelligence reports, 1917
    - U.S. Army. IV Corps, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 5: 6-18)
      Includes information sheets, memoranda, messages, notes, plan of operations (including list of targets), reports, tables, and printed matter.
  - Maps, annotated, 1916-1919 (Map-case folders 8-15)
  - Notebooks on French intelligence operations, 1918 (Box-folder 6: 1-7)
  - Notes of Joseph W. Stilwell, circa 1918 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    Includes J. W. Stillwell American Expeditionary Forces identity card.
  - Official memoranda relating to intelligence operations, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 6: 9-14)
    Includes charts, correspondence, instructions, list of addresses and prisoners, and telegrams.
  - Operation plans, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 7: 1-9)
    Includes plans of defense, reports, memoranda, and maps.
  - Order of battle, IV Corps, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 7: 10-12)
  - Personal correspondence of Joseph W. Stilwell, 1918
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - Hunt, Paul C., 1918 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - Johnson, Archibald M., 1918 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - Lettow Vorbeck, von, Mrs., undated (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - Williams, R. H., 1918 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Personnel records of Intelligence Section, IV Corps, 1918 (Box-folder 7: 18-19)
  - Prisoner interrogation reports, 1918 (Box-folder 8: 1-4)
    Includes lists, maps, and memoranda.
  - Subject file, 1916-1920
    - Aerial intelligence, 1918 (Box-folder 8: 5)
      Pamphlet giving a detailed account of the work of the Branch Intelligence Officer of the Fourth Corps Air Service.
    - Army General Staff College, Langres, France, 1917-1918
      - General, undated (Box-folder 8: 6)
      - First course lectures and map problems, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 8: 7-9)
      - Second course general index, 1918 (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - Second course general lectures, 1918 (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - Numbered lectures, undated (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
      - Conferences, by number, undated (Box-folder 9: 3-11)
      - Map problems, by number, undated (Box-folder 10: 1-9)
      - Notes, undated (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - German surrender, 1918
      - Agreements and terms of armistice, 1918 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - Chronology of events, 1918 (Box-folder 11: 2)
      - Clippings, undated (Box-folder 11: 3)
      - Notes exchanged between the United States and Germany, 1918 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Propaganda, 1918, undated
      - Allied propaganda sent over enemy lines, 1918 (Box-folder 11: 5-8)
      - German propaganda dropped in Allied lines, undated (Box-folder 11: 9-10)
      - German propaganda dropped in Allied lines, undated (Map-case folder 28)
  - Summaries of foreign press, 1918 (Box-folder 111: 2)
    Comprised of printed matter.
  - Summary of intelligence, 1918
    - General (Box-folder 11: 11)
    - I Corps (Box-folder 11: 12-16)
    - II Corps (Box-folder 11: 17-18)
    - III Corps (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - IV Corps (Box-folder 12: 2-5)
  - Telephone messages, 1918
    - August (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - September (Box-folder 12: 7-9)
    - October (Box-folder 12: 10-11)
    - November (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - December (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Training materials for personnel in Intelligence Section, IV Corps, 1916-1920
    - General, circa 1918 (Box-folder 13: 3-7)
    - Bulletin, 1918 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Duties of officers of the G-2 section, circa 1918 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - Instructions, 1917 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - Lectures, Third Division Intelligence School, undated (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Lists of personnel and supplies, circa 1917-1918 (Box-folder 13: 12-13)
      Includes lists of officers and students attending the course and office organization.
    - Manuals of position warfare for all arms, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 14: 1-2)
    - Maps, undated (Map-case folder 27)
    - Memoranda, 1918 (Box-folder 14: 3-5)
    - Notes, including lecture notes, 1918 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Outline for intelligence regulations for machine gun battalions, undated (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Plan of operations, including description of duties of officers, undated (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Printed matter, 1916-1920 (Box-folder 14: 9-10)
    - Reports, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 14: 11-15)
    - Table of intelligence tactics, circa 1918 (Box-folder 111: 8)
    - Schedule of exercises, 1918 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Miscellaneous documents (Box-folder 14: 17)
- China-Burma-India Command File, 1942-1945
  - File 1. "History of the China-Burma-India Theater,", 1945
    Typescript. See also file 28, file 89, file 90, file 110, file 162, file 163, file 165, file 170, and map case/folder 31.
    - Section 1, Master Narrative, undated (Box-folder 15: 1-4)
    - Section 2
      - Part I, North Burma Campaign, 1943 October - 1944 August (Box-folder 15: 5)
      - Part II, The Ledo Road, undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
      - Part III, Y-Force, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 7)
      - Part IV, Z-Force, The Second Thirty Divisions, undated (Box-folder 15: 8)
      - Part V, Ramgarh Training Center, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 9)
      - Part VI
        - a. Army Air Forces, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 15: 10)
          See also map case, folder 27.
        - b. Fourteenth Air Force Activities, 1942 July 4 - 1944 October 31 (Box-folder 15: 11)
          For the final report of Commanding General, U.S. Air Force, China-Burma-India to the U.S. War Dept.
        - c. India-China Division, 1942 December – 1944 October (Box-folder 15: 12)
          General Joseph W. Stilwell's plans for air cargo service over the hump. See also PHOTOGRAPHS/box 96/folder 2.
        - d. Air Service Command, undated (Box-folder 15: 13)
        - e. XX Bomber Command, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 14)
      - Part VII, Services of Supply, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 16: 1)
      - Part VIII, Pipelines, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 2)
        General note
        See also PHOTOGRAPHS/box 96/folder 4 and map case/folder 43.
      - Part IX, Development of Ports, circa 1942 (Box-folder 16: 3)
        See also PHOTOGRAPHS/box 96/folder 2.
      - Part X, Assam Lines of Communication, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 4)
      - Part XI, Lend-Lease to China, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 16: 5)
      - Part XII, Reconstruction of the Burma Road, 1944 October 24 (Box-folder 16: 6)
      - Part XIII, Administration and Staff Narratives, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 7-10)
      - Part XIV, Galahad (5307th Composite Unit, Prov.), 1943 September – 1944 June (Box-folder 16: 11-13)
    - Section 3
      - Part I, Political Reports, 1942 (Box-folder 16: 14)
      - Part II, American Volunteer Group, 1942 (Box-folder 17: 1)
      - Part III, Mission to China, Preparatory Planning, 1942 (Box-folder 17: 2)
      - Part IV (not received by the Hoover Institution) (Box-folder 17: 3)
      - Part V, Notes on Burma Campaign, undated (Box-folder 17: 4)
      - Part VI, "Chinese Fillers Fly the Hump,", undated (Box-folder 17: 5)
      - Part VII, Somervell-Arnold-Dill Mission, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 6-8)
      - Part VIII, Study of Routes to China, undated (Box-folder 17: 9)
      - Part IX, Airfield Construction, circa 1942 (Box-folder 17: 10)
      - Part X, Historical and Political Setting, undated (Box-folder 17: 11-13)
      - Part XI, China Exchange, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 17: 14)
      - Part XII, War Area Service Command, undated (Box-folder 17: 15)
      - Part XIII, Radio Reaction to Joseph W. Stilwell's Recall, 1944 (Box-folder 17: 16)
      - Part XIV, Appendix No. 9, Death Gratuities, undated (Box-folder 17: 17)
  - File 2. Operations plan of the "Step Child" operation, 1943 (Box-folder 18: 1-3)
    See also PHOTOGRAPHS/box 96/folder 1.
  - File 3. Report on specified roads in the Myitkyina area, by Lt. Col. W. E. C. Roper, 1943 November (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - File 4. Third Indian Division
    - Maps, undated (Map-case folder 30)
    - Memoranda, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - Messages and telegrams, undated (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - Notes and minutes of meetings, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - Reports, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - File 5. Y-Force supplies
    - Memoranda and messages, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    - Status reports of equipment, supplies, and troops, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 10)
      See also map case, folder 30.
  - File 6. Somervell-Arnold-Dill Mission, 1943 February (Box-folder 18: 11-14)
    Complete set of final papers in connection with the American-British Conference, February 1-3, 1943, and the Chinese-American-British Conference, February 9, 1943. Includes minutes of meetings and reports. See also map case, folder 30.
  - File 7. Third Indian Division
    - General, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Chronology of air supply, 1944 May - June (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Field orders, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - Memoranda, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - Outline of plan, undated (Box-folder 19: 6)
    - Telegrams, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - File 8. Maps of North Burma and Yunnan, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 8)
    See also map case, folder 37.
  - Files 9-10. Drafts of "Campaign in Burma,", 1942 March 10 - June 1 (Box-folder 19: 9-14)
    Typescript. See also map case, folders 33 and 37.
  - File 11. Washington preparatory planning file
    - General, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 16)
      Includes T. V. Soong’s letters to Henry L. Stimson and John J. McCloy.
    - Memoranda, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 19: 17-19)
    - Notes on China given to H. A. Drum by Dwight D. Eisenhower, undated (Box-folder 19: 20)
    - Report, 1942 (Box-folder 19: 21)
  - File 12. Messages, undated (Box-folder 19: 22)
  - Files 13-13a. Correspondence between Joseph W. Stilwell, Chiang Kai-shek, and Madame Chiang Kai-shek, 1942 May 26 - August 1 (Box-folder 19: 23-25)
    Includes memoranda and notes regarding division of air power.
  - File 14. Data on the Joint Staff, Chinese Armies and Divisions, and the Hankow operation
    - Charts and regulations governing the organization of the Joint Staff of the China War Area, undated (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - Conference proceedings, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - Correspondence
      - Currie, Lauchlin, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 3)
      - Soong, T. V., 1942 (Box-folder 20: 4)
    - Lists of names of accredited representatives for Joint Military Conference and principal stocks, undated (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Map, undated (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - Memoranda, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 7)
      Includes Lauchlin Currie's memorandum to Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - Report, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - File 15. Memoranda on Lend-Lease, Chinese army, and proposed plan for opening a second Pacific front, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 20: 10)
    Includes a letter from Chiang Kai-shek to General Lin.
  - File 16. The Woon Case
    - General, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 11)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 12)
    - Lists and tables, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 13)
    - Memoranda, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 20: 14)
  - File 17. Data on the Northern Area Combat Command (NCAC)
    - Lists of artillery liaison assignments, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 15)
    - Memoranda, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 16)
    - Status reports, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 17)
    - Telegrams, undated (Box-folder 20: 18)
  - Files 18-19. Memoranda, including between Joseph W. Stilwell and Chiang Kai-shek, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 19)
  - File 20. "A Short History of the Army Ground Forces," chapters I and II, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 20: 20)
    Typescript
  - File 21.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 21)
      - Chiang Kai-shek correspondence, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 22)
        Including with Joseph W. Stilwell appointing him Commander-in-Chief to reorganize, train, and direct the Chinese forces in India.
      - Correspondence between Archibald Wavell and Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 23)
    - List of officers of the government of China and China's assaulting armies, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 24)
      See also map case, folder 38.
    - Maps, undated (Map-case folder 37)
    - Memoranda from Joseph W. Stilwell., 1942-1943 (Box-folder 20: 25)
      Memoranda includes those to the Secretary of War on air operations, the medical situation in Burma and Assam, Chiang Kai-shek, and Lend-Lease transfers. Also includes notes on Lend-Lease transfers and Joseph W. Stilwell’s notes on personnel of the 10th air force.
    - Messages, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 26)
      Including messages regarding future shipments of Lend-Lease materials consigned to China, from T. V. Soong to Joseph W. Stilwell supporting his advocacy of re-armament plan, and summary of important messages.
    - Outline of estimate and plan to be prepared by the Joint Staff, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 27)
    - Proposal for a "Pacific Front,", undated (Box-folder 20: 28)
    - Reports, 1942 (Box-folder 20: 29)
      Scope and Contenets
      Including of withdrawal of the 200th Chinese Division to China.
    - Translation of General Lo Cho-ying's report to Chiang Kai-shek on the operations of the Chinese Expeditionary Force in Burma, 1942 June 25 (Box-folder 20: 30)
  - File 22.
    - Letter from Clayton L. Bissell to Joseph W. Stilwell on efficiency rating of Claire Lee Chennault, 1943 (Box-folder 21: 1)
      Includes report.
    - Map of the route of the 2nd Division, undated (Box-folder 21: 2)
    - Observations of the Royal Air Force in Burma, undated (Box-folder 21: 3)
    - Reports on activities
      - 93rd Division, undated (Box-folder 21: 4)
      - 49th Division in Burma, 1942 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - File 23. (not received by the Hoover Institution) (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - File 24. Notes on problems connected with the mission in China, 1944 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - File 25. Hoarding by the Chinese in Y-Force, 1944 October
    - Letters from Frank Dorn and T. F. Taylor, 1944 October 10 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Memoranda, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 9)
    - Messages, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 10)
    - Report, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - File 26. Platoon test, 124th Cavalry., 1944 October (Box-folder 21: 12)
    Includes general comments, critiques, and reports.
  - File 27. Strength report, Ramgarh, 1944 October (Box-folder 21: 13)
  - File 28. Drafts for various chapters of "History of the China-Burma-India Theater,", undated (Box-folder 21: 14-15)
  - File 29.
    - Drafts, lists, and reports, 1943 September – October (Box-folder 20: 16)
    - Letter about the Services of Supply, U.S. Army forces in China, 1943 September 24 (Box-folder 20: 17)
    - Notes on training, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 18)
    - Status reports on trucks, units, and tanks, 1943 (Box-folder 20: 19)
  - File 30.
    - Directive from Louis Mountbatten and A. C. Wedemeyer, 1944 July 23 (Box-folder 21: 20)
    - Letter from Feng Yu-hsiang to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 August 4 (Box-folder 20: 21)
    - Maps and organizational chart, East China, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 22)
    - Memorandum regarding the 77th Brigade from Louis Mountbatten to Joseph W. Stilwell, undated (Box-folder 21: 23)
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to Louis Mountbatten, 1944 July 19 (Box-folder 21: 24)
    - Memorandum from F. L. Eldridge to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 August 24 (Box-folder 21: 25)
    - Memorandum from M. K. Barroll to Daniel Sultan, 1944 September 3 (Box-folder 21: 26)
    - Summary of proposed South East Asia Command Operations, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 21: 27)
  - File 31.
    - Code messages, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 1)
    - Letter from Joseph W. Stilwell to Chief of Staff, U.S. Army, 1944 May 27 (Box-folder 22: 2)
    - Letters from Claire Lee Chennault to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 April – May (Box-folder 22: 3)
    - Maps, undated (Map-case folder 34)
    - Memoranda regarding the situation in Eastern China and plan of defense, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Memoranda from Daniel Sultan to Joseph W. Stilwell and George E. Stratemeyer, 1944 May 22 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Memoranda, including from J. E. Hull to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 June 9 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - Ordnance inventories in depots, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - Telegrams, including with Claire Lee Chennault, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - File 32. G-3 situation reports, 1944 April (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - File 33.
    - G-2 reports, 1944 June (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - G-2 telegrams, including between Joseph W. Stilwell and Hayden L. Boatner regarding Myitkyina, undated (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Situation maps (overlays) of Myitkyina and maps showing Merrill's Marauders' advance on Myitkyina, undated (Map-case folders 33 and 37)
  - File 34.
    - Directives, letters, and memoranda relating to the South East Asia Command, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Memorandum from Daniel Sultan to Frank Merrill, 1944 June 23 (Box-folder 22: 13)
    - Memorandum from Frank Merrill to Daniel Sultan, 1944 June 28 (Box-folder 22: 14)
    - Memorandum from Daniel Sultan to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 July 2 (Box-folder 22: 15)
    - Memorandum from George E. Stratemeyer to Louis Mountbatten, 1944 July 7 (Box-folder 22: 16)
  - File 35.
    - G-3 correspondence, undated (Box-folder 22: 17)
    - Letters from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 April 16, 19, and 28 (Box-folder 22: 18)
    - Memorandum from Claire Lee Chennault to the Commanding General, U.S. Air Force, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 19)
    - Y-Force maps, memoranda, supply lists, and telegrams, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 20)
  - File 36. Data on First Thirty Divisions and Chinese Expeditionary Force
    - Letter from George E. Stratemeyer to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 21)
    - Lists and tables, 1943 (Box-folder 22: 22)
    - Memoranda, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 23)
    - Notes, undated (Box-folder 22: 24)
  - File 37.
    - General order, no. 1, American Army Forces, China-Burma-India, 1942 March 4 (Box-folder 22: 25)
    - Letter from W. Mason Wright to John L. Mott, 1945 (Box-folder 22: 26)
    - Memorandum from K. W. Tracey to W. Mason Wright, 1945 March 3 (Box-folder 22: 27)
    - Memorandum from Joseph W. Stilwell to the Chief of Staff, U.S. Army, 1945 March 5 (Box-folder 22: 28)
    - Memorandum to K. R. Greenfield, 1945 March 16 (Box-folder 22: 29)
    - Miscellany, 1944 (Box-folder 22: 30)
  - File 38. Maps of Eastern China, undated (Box-folder 22: 31)
  - File 39.
    - Letter from Hayden L. Boatner to Daniel Sultan, 1944 July 21 (Box-folder 22: 32)
    - Map relating to intelligence, memoranda, and operational reports, 1944 July (Box-folder 22: 33)
      Includes a letter from Hayden L. Boatner to Daniel L. Sultan, 1944. See also map case, folder 37.
  - File 40. Letters and memoranda relating to use of air resources by large scale movements of troops and supplies by air, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
  - File 41. U.S. War Dept. circulars relating to awards and decorations, 1943 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - File 42.
    - Letter from Pai Ch'ung-hsi to Joseph W. Stilwell about Kweilin, the Clarke affair, and tonnage, 1943 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Manifesto, "China's Duty,", undated (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Memoranda relating to radio training, 1943 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Files 43-43a.
    - Unidentified letter to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - Final report on B-29 bases in India, 1944 November (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - Notes from Joseph W. Stilwell to Daniel Sultan, undated (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - Notes on issuance of communiqués and press releases, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 10)
  - File 44.
    - Army Group operation instruction, no. 4, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 11)
    - General order, no. 74, 1944 July 17 (Box-folder 23: 12)
    - Memoranda, including instructions for monsoon operations, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 13)
    - Report on Fort Hertz area, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 14)
  - File 45.
    - Letter from Louis Mountbatten to George Marshall, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 15)
    - Letters from Louis Mountbatten to Joseph W. Stilwell regarding the Long Range Patrol Brigades, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 16)
    - Miscellany, 1944 (Box-folder 23: 17)
  - File 46.
    - Letter and telegrams from Archibald Wavell to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 July 29, November 16-17, December 7 (Box-folder 23: 18)
    - Letter from Joseph W. Stilwell to Archibald Wavell, 1942 November 8 (Box-folder 23: 19)
  - File 47. Memorandum from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwell regarding survey of China-Burma-India Theater, 1943 June 29 (Box-folder 23: 20)
  - File 48.
    - Memoranda on food dropped on Chinese troops in India by Frank Merrill, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 21)
    - Report on food dropped for Chinese troops, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 22)
      Includes Exhibit B, maps; and Exhibit C, summary of supplies dropped since June 29, 1942. See PHOTOGRAPHS, box 96, folder 2 for Exhibit A, prints of refugee camps.
  - File 49.
    - "Final report of the Combined Chiefs of Staff to the President and Prime Minister,", 1943 May 25 (Box-folder 23: 23)
    - Minutes of the 6th Trident meeting at the White House, 1943 May 25 (Box-folder 23: 24)
      Includes annex of proposals to be made to Chiang Kai-shek.
    - "Report of the Combined Chiefs of Staff Relating to the Implementation of Assumed Basic Undertakings and Specific Operations for the Conduct of the War, 1943-1944,", 1943 May 25 (Box-folder 23: 25)
  - File 50.
    - Charts, lists, and tables relating to the organization of the Ramgarh project, undated (Box-folder 23: 26)
    - Excerpt from Harijan, "Foreign Soldiers in India," by M. K. Gandhi, 1942 April 26 (Box-folder 23: 27)
  - File 51.
    - Memoranda on Indian politics from John P. Davies to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 28)
    - Paraphrased messages from Lauchlin Currie and Chiang Kai-shek to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1942 August 11, November 11 (Box-folder 23: 29)
  - File 52. Instructions, lists, and memoranda relating to the Y-Force, Chinese artillery, and Chinese army officers, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 30-31)
  - File 53.
    - Correspondence relating to the China Air Task Force, 1942 October-December (Box-folder 23: 32)
    - Memoranda relating to the China Air Task Force, 1942 September (Box-folder 23: 33)
  - File 54.
    - Letter from Shang Chen to John Magruder, 1942 April 24 (Box-folder 23: 34)
      Scope and Contens
      Letter conveying Chiang Kai-shek's order appointing Joseph W. Stilwell as Chief of Staff, Headquarters of the Supreme Commander of the Allied Forces, China War Theater.
    - Special order from Chiang Kai-shek issued by the National Government Military Committee appointing Joseph W. Stilwell as the Chief Commander of the Chinese army in India, 1942 July 11 (Box-folder 23: 35)
  - File 55.
    - Memoranda and notes on training of the Chinese Expeditionary Force, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 23: 36)
    - Memoranda from Joseph W. Stilwell to George C. Marshall, and from T. V. Soong to Joseph W. Stilwell, 1943 January 19 (Box-folder 23: 37)
    - Notes on program for preparation of the Y-Force and on the tactical doctrine of the Japanese Army, 1943 (Box-folder 23: 38)
  - File 56.
    - Burma war plans, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 39-42)
    - Memoranda between Joseph W. Stilwell and Chiang Kai-shek, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 43)
      Includes memoranda from Dwight D. Eisenhower to the Chief of Staff, from John Magruder to Chiang Kai-shek, from Frank Merrill to Joseph W. Stilwell, and from T. V. Soong to Joseph W. Stilwell.
    - Minutes of meetings at Chiang Kai-shek's New Delhi residence, 1942 February 15-16 (Box-folder 23: 44)
    - U.S. British report concerning assistance to China, 1942 (Box-folder 23: 45)
  - File 57. Interim report by the Joint British-American Staff Committee, 1943 February 9 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - File 58. Memorandum from R. A. Wheeler to Joseph W. Stilwell regarding plans for Services of Supply mission, 1942 November 4 (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - File 59. Memorandum from Frank Dorn to Joseph W. Stilwell, regarding the defeat of Japan, 1943 March 29 (Box-folder 24: 3)